everytownresearch.org 2019-08-09

# Privacy Policy - EverytownResearch.org

**Everytown for Gun Safety Support Fund Privacy Statement**

_Updated: July 26, 2019_

This Privacy Policy is offered by Everytown for Gun Safety Support Fund, Inc. (“we,” “us,” or “our”) to describe the information collection, use, and disclosure practices of our websites that link to this Privacy Policy (“Sites”) as well as for the personal information that we receive through other channels including by postal mail or in person. 

**Information Collection**

When you visit our Sites or otherwise interact with us, we may collect certain personal information you choose to disclose to us, such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, and payment card information. You may provide this information, for example, when you send a donation, register with the Sites, make a purchase, or send a message on the Sites. If you register with the Sites, you may also be asked to create a user name and password. We may also receive information about you from third parties and combine it with the information that you provide.

When you interact with us, such as when you make a donation or provide your information through the Sites, your personal information, including your email, will automatically be added to our mailing list. Email addresses of recipients of tell-a-friend emails will not be collected by us.

If you apply for a job with us, we will collect any information that you provide during the application process, including your contact information, educational and work history, and demographic and other information that you submit about yourself.

We (or third parties as described below) may also collect technical information about your visit to our Sites, such as your domain name, IP address, browser type, activities on the Sites, and date and time of your visit.

**Information Use**

We may use the information we collect for any lawful purpose, such as to:

  * respond to your requests;
  * send information to you about Everytown for Gun Safety Support Fund or other organizations;
  * operate and improve the Sites, and customize your experience;
  * comply with applicable law;
  * identify or remedy potential threats to the Sites’ security;
  * conduct research about your use of the Sites and our services; and
  * for any other purpose stated at the time of collection.

**Cookies**

The Sites are cookie-enabled to give you a more customized user experience. A cookie is a small piece of information that a website can store on a computer and later use to recognize a user. A purpose of cookies is to enhance your ability to receive the information you want. We use two types of cookies to enhance the experience of users: session cookies and persistent cookies. A session cookie expires when a user closes the browser in which this website was viewed. A persistent cookie expires on a pre-determined date. You may be able to personalize your browser settings to reject cookies, although certain features of the Sites may not function as intended. See below for more information and choices regarding analytics and interest-based advertising by third parties on the Sites. 

**Information Sharing**

We may share personal information with our affiliates, such as parent or subsidiary organizations.

From time to time, we may send you information from or share your personal information with other non-affiliated organizations we think you might find interesting. When we share information with such organizations, it will be governed by their privacy policies. If you request that we keep your donation anonymous, we will not share personal information from that donation with non-affiliated organizations as described in this paragraph. Please see “Your Choices” below for more information on opting out. 

We may share personal information with third parties who support our work, such as service providers, affiliates, and subsidiaries. This may include sharing information about your donations and purchases with third parties that provide marketing analytics services to us and to other entities based on the information that we provide. As a result of this sharing, such other entities will be able to send you more relevant offers if you already have a relationship with them. If you request that we keep your donation anonymous, we will not share personal information from that donation for marketing analytics as described in this paragraph. Please see “Your Choices” below for more information on opting out. 

If we or some or all of our assets are acquired by another organization, such as through a merger, acquisition, or bankruptcy, that organization will possess the information collected by us, and it will assume the rights and obligations regarding your information as described in this Privacy Policy.

We may disclose personal information or other data to comply with law or legal requirements, enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements, or protect our rights, property, or safety of our users or others.

We may share information that has been de-identified or aggregated, or any other technical information, without limitation.

Some parts of the Sites allow you to interact with other visitors or to participate in public forums. When you participate in these features, such as by commenting, the information that you provide will be available to other Site visitors and/or the general public.

**Third Party Links and Tools**

For your convenience, the Sites may contain certain hyperlinks to other websites offered by third parties. We make no promises or guarantees regarding data collection on the hyperlinked pages that are not operated by Everytown for Gun Safety Support Fund. 

The Sites may also include tools offered by third parties, such as our donations page, and social media tools or “plug-ins” from third parties, such as social networking and video streaming tools. If you create accounts with these third parties, use their tools on our Sites, or otherwise interact with these third parties on any Site, the third parties may collect, use, and share such information in accordance with your account settings, including by sharing such information with the general public. With respect to donations, our third-party partner may provide your donation information to us for our own use.

Your interactions with third-party entities and your use of their features and websites are governed by the privacy notices of the entities that provide those features. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy notices of any accounts and tools that you use.

**Your Choices**

If you would like to opt out of our sharing of your information with other organizations for them to contact you, including for the marketing analytics services described above, you can email us at info@everytown.org. 

You can unsubscribe from the Everytown for Gun Safety Support Fund emailing list at any time by following the instructions included within any email you receive from us. You can unsubscribe from our direct mail list at any time by emailing us at [info@everytown.org](mailto:info@everytown.org). 

If you would no longer like to receive offers from other organizations, you can unsubscribe by following the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of each email communication that you receive from them.

**Analytics and Interest-Based Advertising**

IWe may work with third parties to serve more relevant online ads to you based on information we collect about you and information those third parties collect about your activities on our Sites and across other websites and apps over time, including on different devices. We adhere to the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) Self-Regulatory Principles in connection with this activity. You may visit www.aboutads.info to learn more about such Interest-Based Advertising (“IBA”) and how to opt-out of this type of advertising by companies participating in the DAA self-regulatory program. To opt out of IBA from participating members of the Network Advertising Initiative, you may visit  www.networkadvertising.org. 

We may also work with third parties that collect data about your use of the Sites and other websites or apps over time for non-advertising purposes. We use Google Analytics and other third-party services to improve the performance of the Sites and for analytics and marketing purposes. For more information about how Google Analytics collects and uses data when you use our Sites, visit <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>, and to opt out of Google Analytics, visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>.

**Updating Your Information**

You may request to review, change, or update your contact information previously provided to us, by emailing us at [info@everytown.org](mailto:info@everytown.org). 

**Policy Updates**

From time to time, we may update this Privacy Policy. We will notify you of any material changes to our Privacy Policy by updating this webpage and the effective date. We encourage you periodically to check this webpage to learn about the information we collect, use, and share. Your continued use of the Sites or other continued interactions with us will affirm your agreement to such changes.

**Contact Us**

Please contact us if you have questions about our Privacy Policy at [info@everytown.org](mailto:info@everytown.org).
